here's one way to make sense of the
alternating sums of the powers of
one-half start with this nomon shaped
object here and assume that it has area
one we can divide the gnomon into four
smaller gnomons and remove two of them
so we removed half and then we can add
one of those back adding one-fourth back
now we can repeat this process on the
added back nomon removing half and then
adding one half of that back we can
continue this process indefinitely each
time we re-add one of the gnomons we
divide it into four nomons remove two
and then add one back we can continue
this process forever or indefinitely and
it turns out that we've shaded the
infinite sum of the alternating powers
of one-half on the other hand if we look
at the picture we see that we've shaded
exactly two-thirds of the diagram so the
sum of the powers of negative one-half
must be equal to two-thirds